the-big-bang-theory.com 2019-05-25

# The Big Bang Theory Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

#### What we collect:

The Big Bang Theory Site collects log files of visitors' activity on the site. These log files include your IP address, the time and date of your visit, technical data about the connection you make to the website and our server's response, the page or files you access on the site, the full address of a website which referred you here (including external websites; can also include search terms) where applicable, and technical information about your browser, operating system and any browser plugins. A log entry is recorded for every page you view, every file loaded by your browser, and every action which calls back to the server (eg. voting in a poll).

We will use geolocation services to gain an approximate idea of your location based on your IP address, usually down to the city or town level, to provide more localised content. Your country and city may also be stored alongside actions you take on the website [eg. voting in polls, rating episodes, entering contests] and may be publicly displayed. We may also store technical information about your browser, computer or network alongside your actions on the website, although this information will not be publicly displayed.

The Big Bang Theory Site may also collect more personal information in interactive areas of the website. These may include your name, nickname, e-mail address, or physical address where appropriate. Interactive areas of the site, such as contests, may provide more detail on how that information will be used.

#### Interactive Areas:

When you interact with our website, for example by voting in a poll, we will record information about your action on our server. Alongside the content you submit [eg. your choice in a poll] we will also collect information about you.

This information may be used to limit the number of times people can vote, to publicly show information about voters [eg. a user from France just voted in this poll], or so we can keep track of entries in a contest.

**Polls:  **When you vote in a poll, we will also record the time and date, and your country and city based on geolocation data. We will publicly display your vote alongside your country and city.

**Quote Submissions:  **When you submit a quote to the website, we will also record your IP address and the time and date alongside your quote.

**Contests:  **When you enter a contest, we will record your name, email address, your IP address, your country, the time and date, and we may also ask for your physical address.

**Episode Tournaments:  **When you vote in an episode tournament, we will also record your IP address, your network hostname, a unique user ID which we set, your country and city based on geolocation data, your browser, any website which referred you to the site, the number of pages you have viewed on the site, the first page you viewed on the site and the time you did so, and the time and date of your vote.

**Episode Ratings:  **When you rate an episode, we will also collect your IP address, and your city and country based on geolocation data. We will publicly display the country and city.

**Quote / Clothing Searches:  **When you perform a search on our quote or clothing pages, we will record the query, the time and date, the number of results you received, the number of searches you make, and a unique user ID we set for that session. We do not collect your IP address.

**Admin / System Logs:  **To help us protect the website and diagnose problems, we may also log errors and record actions taken in secure areas of the website. These logs will contain contextual information about the error/action, your IP address, and the time and date.

Find out what information we currently hold about you with our [**Your Data tool**](https://the-big-bang-theory.com/your-data/).

#### What we do with your information:

Our log files are solely used to monitor traffic to this website and to maintain the server's security. We do not combine or use the log files in conjunction with any other data we, or any third-party, hold.

Personal information we collect will only be used for the explicit purpose for which it was collected [eg. entering a contest, submitting a quote]. We will not use this information to develop a profile of you, either for our own use or for the use of any third-party. This information will not be used to target, advertise or market to you, nor assist any other party in doing so.

You may, in the process of using this site, choose to provide your information to third parties acting on our behalf. In all instances it will be made clear who is operating the service should you wish to consult their privacy policies.

#### Who we share it with:

We do not share our server log files with anybody outside of this website except where required by law.

We do not share personal information with anybody outside of this website, except when required to by law or where it is explicitly noted.

The following companies are able to collect data through scripts on this website: [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), [Google Adsense](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), [Amazon.com](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496), [Amazon.co.uk](https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010). They may use non-personal information related to your visits to this and other participating sites to target advertising based on your generic interests ("behavioral advertising").

You can [**opt-out of behavioral advertising at the Network Advertising Initiative website**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). This will stop behavioral advertisement targeting by Google and other listed publishers. You may also [opt-out of Google's program on their website](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/view).

#### Where the data is held:

All data submitted to this site is held on our server in the United States of America. Backups and copies of this data may exist elsewhere in other competent jurisdictions.

 **By using this site you consent for your data to be stored & processed in the United States of America, where the data protection laws may offer lesser protection than the laws of your country.**

#### How long it's held for:

We keep no more than two months' log files on the server. This means the log file for January will be deleted at the start of March.

We will delete or anonymize data from user interactions with our website [eg. poll votes, episode ratings] thirty days after they are first recorded. Where there is a need to keep data for longer [eg. tournaments which run for more than thirty days], the thirty-day retention period begins on the first day we stop collecting information.

Our data removal policy does not mean a user action is undone or will never have happened. For example, poll voting counts will not be adjusted down when we remove the voting entry. We will delete individual user entries or strip out any personal information, such as an IP address, from the records.

#### The use of cookies:

This web site will set cookies with your computer. You can find more information about our use of cookies in our [Cookie Policy](https://the-big-bang-theory.com/cookies/).

Companies who provide services for us may also place cookies on your computer. These cookies track viewing behaviour across this site and other sites in their network for the purposes of advertising or statistic gathering. The information they collect through, or on behalf of, this website, is not personally identifiable.

#### Any questions or requests:

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or the data we hold on you, please email us at **ADMIN [AT] THE-BIG-BANG-THEORY.COM.**

Find out what information we currently hold about you with our [**Your Data tool**](https://the-big-bang-theory.com/your-data/). You can also use that tool to send a data access request to receive a copy of the information we hold about you.

#### Legal Notice.

No part of this site is targeted at minors under the age of 13 years, we expressly prohibit use of this site by people under the age of 13 or those under the age of 18 without their guardian's consent.

**This site complies with the United States COPPA and does not knowingly collect the personal information of minors under the age of 13yrs.**

This privacy policy was last updated May 25, 2018.
